A Finding Aid to the Florence Arquin Papers, 1923-1985, in the Archives of American Art AAA.arquflor
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1923-1964; Series 5; 1.8 Linear feet Box 5-7, 11
  - Book Jacket, circa 1929 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Blank Postcards, circa 1940-circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art, by Others, circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Clippings, Scanned with Box 5, F29-36, circa 1930-circa 1960 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
- Photographs, 1929-circa 1960; Series 6; 0.7 Linear feet Box 7, 11
  Photographs include portraits and snapshots of Florence Arquin, Diego Rivera, Frida Kahlo, and other friends, family and colleagues. Photographs of Florence Arquin depict her giving lectures, in her office, with others, and at events. Photographs of Frida Kahlo and Diego Rivera were taken by Florence Arquin, some depict the artists together and others individually. Some of the photos of Diego Rivera depict the artist at work and in his studio. Other photographs are of ruins, festivals, and events taken during Arquin's travels through Latin America.
  Also found are photographs of works of art by Diego Rivera.
  Some photographs are duplicates of those found in the Scrapbooks.
  - Florence Arquin, circa 1935-circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Florence Arquin, With Others, circa 1936-circa 1951 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, F2
  - Florence Arquin, Giving a Lecture, circa 1940 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Florence Arquin, at the International Colloquium on Loso-Brazilian Studies, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Florence Arquin, at Events in Mexico, 1951 February (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Diego Rivera, 1929-circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, 1932-1948 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Frida Kahlo, 1932-1948 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Family, Friends, and Colleagues, circa 1940-circa 1951 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Alario Atano (?)
    Alice Rahon Fitzgerald
    Carlos Meneola
  - Funeral of Jean Manzon, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Ruins and Festivals in Latin America, circa 1930-circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Works of Art (Box 7)
    - by Frida Kahlo, circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 24-25)
    - by Diego Rivera, A-B (5x7), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - by Diego Rivera, C-E (5x7), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - by Diego Rivera, F-M (5x7), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - by Diego Rivera, N-P (5x7), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - by Diego Rivera, R-Z (5x7), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - by Diego Rivera, Untitled or Unidentified (5x7), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - by Diego Rivera, A-C (8x10), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - by Diego Rivera, D-L (8x10), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - by Diego Rivera, M-P (8x10), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - by Diego Rivera, Q-V (8x10), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - by Diego Rivera, Untitled or Unidentified (8x10), circa 1960 (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11, F3
    - Medieval and Renaissance Art, circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified, circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Oversized Photographs, Scanned with Box 7, F14, 36-37, circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
- Artwork, circa 1940-circa 1950; Series 7; 2 Folders Box 7, 11
  Found is one sketchbook by Florence Arquin circa 1940 and two prints signed by de Diego. The sketchbook includes watercolor and pencil sketches.
  - Sketchbook, circa 1940 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Prints, by de Diego, circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Scrapbooks, 1935-1956; Series 8; 0.9 Linear feet Box 8-10
  Found are four scrapbooks, likely created by Florence Arquin and roughly organized by events. Scrapbooks relate to Arquin's work with the Federal Art Project while at the Art Institite of Chicago; a trip to Mexico in 1943; the Kodachrome Slide Project; and Arquin's travel though Latin America. Included are photographs, writings, maps, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and clippings.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1935-1939 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Found are materials relating to Arquin's work with the Federal Art Project at at the Art Institute of Chicago with education and outreach. Included are photographs of exhibitions; Florence Arquin, Holger Cahill and others; student works of art; and clippings, exhibition announcements and other printed materials.
  - Scrapbook 2, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Found are materials relating to Arquin's trip to Mexico in 1943. Included are photographs, clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and writings. Photographs are of Florence Arquin, Helen O'Gorman, Walter Pach, Diego Rivera, Lupe Rivera, and Dr. Charles Stevens.
  - Scrapbook 3, 1945-1948 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Found are materials relating to the Kodachrome Slide Project and Arquin's travels through Latin America. Included are photographs, clippings, and exhibition materials.
  - Scrapbook 4, 1950-1956 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Found are materials relating to the Kodachrome Slide Project and Arquin's travels through Latin America. Included are photographs, writings, maps, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and clippings.